<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>brereton.me</title>
    <link>https://brereton.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on brereton.me</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2017 18:29:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://brereton.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum Vitae</title>
      <link>https://brereton.me/brereton-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2017 18:29:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brereton.me/brereton-cv/</guid>
      <description>Andrew E. Brereton A formally trained structural biologist with an emphasis in data science and visualization, machine learning, and software development. Research interests are varied but include neurobiology, human/animal intelligence, sleep biology, aging, perception, and protein structure/design problems.
Peer-reviewed Publications Brereton AE, Karplus PA, &amp;ldquo;Ensemblator v3: Robust Atom-level Comparative Analyses and Classification of Protein Structure Ensembles.&amp;rdquo; Protein Sci. (2017). DOI: 10.1002/pro.3249
Nelson KJ, Perkins A, Van Swearingen AED, Hartman A, Brereton AE, Parsonage D, Salsbury FR, Karplus PA, and Poole LB.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing a Tattoo Using Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://brereton.me/blog/tattoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brereton.me/blog/tattoo/</guid>
      <description>When I design a tattoo I like it to mean something personally to me. I also like for it to be unique, and to reflect my personality. With that in mind, I hoped to create a tattoo that would show some of the things I had learned here at OSU, while I was getting my PhD. I think I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to pull that off, and I&amp;rsquo;ll try to detail a little about how I made the tattoo here in this blog post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Time I Broke My Arm</title>
      <link>https://brereton.me/writing/the_time_i_broke_my_arm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brereton.me/writing/the_time_i_broke_my_arm/</guid>
      <description>Involved Parties:  Andrew Brereton Zach Ruggles Delia Brereton (my Mom)  The Story I used to live in Canada, until recently. I lived near a small town called Parry Sound; it was an eleven-minute drive into town from my house, and I lived at the top of a small hill overlooking a lake. In the summer it was warm and nice, and in the winter it was cold and entirely covered in snow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mutants Among Us: the unexpected effects of a mutation in AMPD1</title>
      <link>https://brereton.me/blog/mutants/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brereton.me/blog/mutants/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve become interested in the effects of a particular mutation. The mutation is a single nucleotide polymorphism (SNP) in a protein called Adenosine Monophosphate Deaminase 1 (AMPD1). In this case, the nucleotide base at this position was supposed to be a &amp;ldquo;C&amp;rdquo; (cytosine), but it&amp;rsquo;s been changed to a &amp;ldquo;T&amp;rdquo; (thymine). This single letter mutation has been called &amp;ldquo;the most prevalent genetic disease mutation&amp;rdquo;, at least in Caucasians1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter</title>
      <link>https://brereton.me/writing/winter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brereton.me/writing/winter/</guid>
      <description>No wonder then, that Winter feels so unreal;
when the trees finally fall to their dreaming,
leaving the warm-blooded to their feverish movements,
like scratches of ink on a clean white page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evening Sky</title>
      <link>https://brereton.me/writing/evening-sky/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brereton.me/writing/evening-sky/</guid>
      <description>A sliver of moon,
an airplane&amp;rsquo;s pale cloudy trail;
hanging in the sky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ozymandius</title>
      <link>https://brereton.me/writing/ozymandius/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brereton.me/writing/ozymandius/</guid>
      <description>Shifting drifts of sand
Lazily etch their message
In the old king&amp;rsquo;s plaque.
Words that used to read
&amp;ldquo;Upon my works, ye mighty
Gaze and feel despair!&amp;rdquo;
Despite my straining,
All I sense is the endless
Whisper of the sands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rainfall</title>
      <link>https://brereton.me/writing/rainfall/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brereton.me/writing/rainfall/</guid>
      <description>Gray skies and
the soft rains fall
to tear the earth
and tease the trees
to struggle for heights.
Dimly then
their scent recalls
in short sweet bursts
old bitter dreams
of ancient paradise.
Now alone
amidst the sounds
of endless drips
upon the ground;
remember,
there is no rest
and no respite
but only tired and dim gray light.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datafest Oregon 2016</title>
      <link>https://brereton.me/blog/datafest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brereton.me/blog/datafest/</guid>
      <description>Datafest Oregon 2016 This year, I competed in Datafest. Datafest is a data analysis competition for students, with a corporate sponsor who provides the data. For this competition Ticketmaster provided the data, and Datafest itself was hosted by Dr. Charlotte Wickham, an assistant professor in the Statistics Department at OSU.
Our team was called &amp;ldquo;Pretty Terrestrial&amp;rdquo;, and consisted of myself, Michelle Wiley, Steven Freidman, and Camden Lopez. It was a lot of fun working together on this project, especially when it got down to crunch time in the final hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Family</title>
      <link>https://brereton.me/writing/the-importance-of-family/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brereton.me/writing/the-importance-of-family/</guid>
      <description>I got out of the car, and shut the door a little too loud. The sound reverberates against the side of the barn, and seems to announce to the world, Stranger. Stranger Here. I know I’m paranoid. I know I feel this way partly because I know they won’t like the reasons why I’ve come here. This is what I have to do though. This is all I can do to make the world a little safer, a little better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a Travel Ukulele</title>
      <link>https://brereton.me/blog/ukulele/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brereton.me/blog/ukulele/</guid>
      <description>Total cost for parts and tools: $64 Time: 2 weeks Emotional damage: minimal  The Motivation So I really like the look to the Risa Solid Uke. However, it&amp;rsquo;s a little too rich for my blood at this point. One day I&amp;rsquo;ll buy one. In the meantime, I thought it might be cool to try to build my own poor man&amp;rsquo;s version (which ended up costing more than I expected).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brewing My First Beer</title>
      <link>https://brereton.me/blog/brewing-my-first-beer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brereton.me/blog/brewing-my-first-beer/</guid>
      <description>I got into homebrewing. I like beer so why wouldn&amp;rsquo;t I enjoy making beer?! For this first beer I ended up making an ESB I call the Fug Vale ESB. It was delicious, I only have two bottles left&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m considering sending one to my brother, but then again, I could just drink it. Sorry Calvin!
Here are a few pictures of that whole process:
Getting Started Some starting materials: yeast and hops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Real Poutine</title>
      <link>https://brereton.me/blog/making-real-poutine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 18:29:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brereton.me/blog/making-real-poutine/</guid>
      <description>A month or two ago I decided I had had enough of the sub-par American so-called poutine I have received here. I miss the cheesy, gravy goodness of my homeland! So I gathered my favorite Americans, and showed them the light (heavy).
The Problems I know I&amp;rsquo;m being a snob, but please forgive me. There are three main problems (in my opinion) with how Americans tend to make poutine:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>